<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="25"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Dr.Rawan elshafey & Dr. Mona Sewelam














                         Specialities of


































































         2025-2026                     pharmacy



         Tips on how to pick your


                    ideal focus]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[26               FOR YOU










                       SPECIALITY






















     Pharmacy is much more than just dispensing medicines—it is a  Pharmacists are also at the forefront of technological advancements  With the rise of personalized medicine, biotechnology, and artificial
     dynamic and diverse field with over 26 specializations, each  in medicine. With the rise of personalized medicine, biotechnology,  intelligence, pharmacy is constantly evolving to meet the needs of
     offering unique opportunities to contribute to healthcare.  and artificial intelligence, pharmacy is constantly evolving to meet the  modern healthcare. Specializations such as pharmaceutical
     Whether you are interested in working directly with patients,  needs of modern healthcare. .Whether you are interested in working  informatics and biopharmaceuticals are becoming increasingly
     researching new treatments, ensuring drug safety, or even  directly with patients, researching new treatments, ensuring drug  important, opening doors to new research, innovative treatments,
     exploring the business side of the industry, there is a place for  safety, or even exploring the business side of the industry, there is a  and improved patient care. Education and continuous learning play a
     you in pharmacy. For those who enjoy patient care, clinical  place for you in pharmacy. For those who enjoy patient care, clinical  key role in this profession. Many pharmacists choose to pursue
     pharmacy provides a chance to work alongside doctors and  pharmacy provides a chance to work alongside doctors and nurses,  advanced degrees or certifications to specialize further and stay
                                                                                   updated with the latest developments in the field. Whether it's
     nurses, ensuring that treatments are safe and effective.  ensuring that treatments are safe and effective.. Community  through postgraduate studies, professional training, or hands-on
     Community pharmacists, on the other hand, play a key role in  pharmacists, on the other hand, play a key role in educating patients  experience, the journey of a pharmacist is one of lifelong learning and
     educating patients and guiding them on proper medication use.  and guiding them on proper medication use. If research and  growth. With so many paths to choose from, pharmacy offers
     If research and innovation excite you, pharmaceutical sciences  innovation excite you, pharmaceutical sciences and drug  something for everyone. Whether you prefer the fast-paced
     and drug development focus on creating and improving  development focus on creating and improving medicines to tackle  environment of a hospital, the precision of a laboratory, or the
     medicines to tackle various health challenges. Some  various health challenges. Some pharmacists specialize in regulatory  strategic thinking required in business and regulation, there is a
     pharmacists specialize in regulatory affairs and  affairs and pharmacovigilance, making sure that medicines meet  specialization that matches your skills and ambitions. This magazine
     pharmacovigilance, making sure that medicines meet safety  safety standards and monitoring their effects after they reach the  will take you on a journey through the many branches of pharmacy,
     standards and monitoring their effects after they reach the  market. Others choose industrial pharmacy, where they oversee the  exploring the roles, challenges, and career opportunities in each field.
     market. Others choose industrial pharmacy, where they oversee  manufacturing and quality control of pharmaceutical products.  Whether you're a student considering your future or a professional
     the manufacturing and quality control of pharmaceutical  Meanwhile, fields like pharmacoeconomics and pharmaceutical  looking to expand your expertise, understanding the full scope of
     products. Meanwhile, fields like pharmacoeconomics and  marketing allow professionals to combine their scientific knowledge  pharmacy will help you find the right path for you. By exploring these
     pharmaceutical marketing allow professionals to combine their  with business strategies to improve healthcare accessibility and  specializations in depth, we aim to provide insights into the impact of
                                          affordability. Pharmacists are also at the forefront of technological
     scientific knowledge with business strategies to improve                      pharmacy on global healthcare, the challenges faced by
     healthcare accessibility and affordability.   advancements in medicine.       professionals in the field, and the future of pharmaceutical sciences.






























                                                       2 I Page]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[CLINICAL PHARMACISTS ARE
                                           HEALTHCARE PROFESSIONALS
                                          SPECIALIZING IN THE RATIONAL
                                              USE OF MEDICATIONS TO
                                           OPTIMIZE PATIENT CARE. THEY
                                                WORK DIRECTLY WITH
                                            PATIENTS, PHYSICIANS, AND
                                          OTHER HEALTHCARE PROVIDERS
                                            TO ENSURE SAFE, EFFECTIVE,
                                                 AND COST-EFFICIENT
                                           MEDICATION THERAPY. UNLIKE
                                             TRADITIONAL PHARMACISTS
                                             WHO PRIMARILY DISPENSE
                                               MEDICATIONS, CLINICAL
                                              PHARMACISTS FOCUS ON
                                           PATIENT-CENTERED CARE AND
                                            MEDICATION MANAGEMENT.





























                                              HOSPITALS AND CLINICS


                                              AMBULATORY CARE CENTERS

                                              ACADEMIA AND RESEARCH


                                              PHARMACEUTICAL INDUSTRY











                                                       3 I Page]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Pharmacists are also at the forefront of technological advancements in medicine. With the rise of personalized medicine, biotechnology,
          and artificial intelligence, pharmacy is constantly evolving to meet the needs of modern healthcare. .Whether you are interested in
          working directly with patients, researching new treatments, ensuring drug safety, or even exploring the business side of the industry,
          there is a place for you in pharmacy. For those who enjoy patient care, clinical pharmacy provides a chance to work alongside doctors
          and nurses, ensuring that treatments are safe and effective.. Community pharmacists, on the other hand, play a key role in educating
          patients and guiding them on proper medication use. If research and innovation excite you, pharmaceutical sciences and drug
          development focus on creating and improving medicines to tackle various health challenges. Some pharmacists specialize in regulatory
          affairs and pharmacovigilance, making sure that medicines meet safety standards and monitoring their effects after they reach the
          market. Others choose industrial pharmacy, where they oversee the manufacturing and quality control of pharmaceutical products.
          Meanwhile, fields like pharmacoeconomics and pharmaceutical marketing allow professionals to combine their scientific knowledge with
          business strategies to improve healthcare accessibility and affordability. Pharmacists are also at the forefront of technological
          advancements in medicine. Pharmacists are also at the forefront of technological advancements in medicine. With the rise of
          personalized medicine, biotechnology, and artificial intelligence, pharmacy is constantly evolving to meet the needs of modern
          healthcare. .Whether you are interested in working directly with patients, researching new treatments, ensuring drug safety, or even
          exploring the business side of the industry, there is a place for you in pharmacy. For those who enjoy patient care, clinical pharmacy
          provides a chance to work alongside doctors and nurses, ensuring that treatments are safe and effective.. Community pharmacists, on
          the other hand, play a key role in educating patients and guiding them on proper medication use. If research and innovation excite you,
          pharmaceutical sciences and drug development focus on creating and improving medicines to tackle various health challenges. Some
          pharmacists specialize in regulatory affairs and pharmacovigilance, making sure that medicines meet safety standards and monitoring
          their effects after they reach the market.







                                                       4 I Page]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[A clinical pharmacist provides direct patient care, medication therapy management and patient counseling. Clinical

          pharmacists work directly with other healthcare professionals to optimize patient care. The clinical pharmacy has spread
          out drastically in terms of its professional services throughout the past few years. Now the clinical pharmacy profession
          has been renowned as an important profession in the multidisciplinary setup of health care. The clinical pharmacist
          becomes a crucial element of healthcare team and promotes patient care by interacting with physician and patient. As

          clinical pharmacists have the precise knowledge about therapeutics and regular interaction with prescribers, they are
          ideally placed to bridge the gap between patients and physicians. Association of clinical pharmacist and clinician can
          provide a strong base for quality assured patient care. The presence of a clinical pharmacist on the ward was a
          revolutionary feature of developments in the pharmacy field. Clinical pharmacists participate in ward rounds with
          physicians and provide their suggestions or recommendations wherever needed. The physicians prescribe medicines
          and the pharmacist checks the prescription to ensure rational use of drugs. They check whether there is an indication for
          the drug, is it the right drug/dose/duration/dosage/time, etc. If there is any deviation from these, they make appropriate

          interventions, inform the prescriber and document the interventions. Complimentary agreement between the physicians
          concerning the impact of the intervention indicates that the pharmacists’ intervention had a confirmed outcome on
          therapy.
          Clinical pharmacists can contribute their efficiencies in medication review, identification of drug related problems,
          therapeutic recommendations and promotion of medication compliance. They obtain medical and medication history,

          check medication errors including prescription, dispensing and administration errors, identify drug interactions, monitor
          adverse drug reactions (ADR), suggest individualization of dosage regimen, provide patient counseling, etc. They also
          provide information about the use of drugs and medical devices like inhaler, insulin pen, eye drops, nasal sprays, etc.



                                                       5 I Page]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[We defined surgical pharmacy as a discipline that studies the

            characteristics of perioperative medication, seeks the most
            suitable medication therapy, and addresses drug-related
            problems for perioperative patients, to improve the clinical
            outcome of these patients.
































                                                             Nutrition pharmacists play a crucial role in improving patient
                                                             outcomes by ensuring that nutritional therapy is safe,

                                                             effective, and tailored to individual needs. Their expertise
                                                             helps prevent complications related to malnutrition and
                                                             nutrient-drug interactions, thereby enhancing the overall
                                                             quality of care.


















                                                       6 I Page]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[7 I Page]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Cosmetic pharmacists employ a rigorous approach to
                              evaluate product safety, scrutinizing ingredients for potential
                              allergens, irritants, or adverse reactions. They ensure that

                              products comply with stringent regulatory standards to
                              safeguard the health and well-being of their clients..














































                                                       8 I Page]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[9 I Page]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[10 I Page]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[It is a specialty area of pharmacy practice involved               Nano pharmacy, also known nanomedicine in pharmacy,

   with the preparation of radioactive materials to                   involves the application of nanotechnology to the
   improve and promote health through the safe and                    development, delivery, and monitoring of
                                                                      pharmaceuticals. This field leverages nanoparticles and
   effective use of radioactive drugs to diagnose and                 nanomaterials to enhance drug efficacy, target specific

   treat specific disease states.                                     tissues or cells, and minimize side effects.
   Nuclear pharmacists compound                                       Pharmaceutical nanotechnology is the exciting, rapidly

   radiopharmaceuticals for nuclear medicine                          emerging branch of medical science that deals with

   departments and outpatient diagnostic clinics.                     harnessing nanoscale materials as drug delivery and/or
                                                                      diagnostic tools. As drug delivery tools, nano-delivery
   The specialty was established by the Board of                      systems can be used to enhance the site-specific,
   Pharmaceutical Specialties (BPS) in 1978, It is a                  targeted delivery of precise medicines. This typically

   specialty area of pharmacy practice involved with                  results in significant reductions in side effects and

   the preparation of radioactive materials to improve                concomitant improvements in efficacy.

   and promote health through the safe and effective                  Nanomedicines have already demonstrated several key
                                                                      advantages, including improved delivery in water-
   use of radioactive drugs to diagnose and treat                     insoluble conditions, extended bioactivity by providing

   specific disease states                                            protection of the “payload” against a potentially

                                                                      destructive biological environment, enhanced transport
                                                                      across epithelial and endothelial barriers, and the ability
                                                                      to combine therapeutic and diagnostic activities. Gold
                                                                      nanoparticles, for instance, can be used as biomarkers
                                                                      and tumor labels for biomolecule detection assays.






















                                                        11 I Page]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[12 I Page]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[CRITICAL CARE PHARMACY










































       Critical care is medical care for people who have life-threatening injuries


       and illnesses. It usually takes place in an intensive care unit (ICU). A


       team of specially-trained health care providers gives you 24-hour care.


       This includes using machines to constantly monitor your vital signs.














                                                        13 I Page]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Severe burns                                        Severe bleeding





              Heart attack                                        Severe Metabolic & Toxic Disorders






              COVID-19                                            Pulmonary embolism





              Heart failure                                       Acute Liver Failure






              Stroke                                              Polytrauma with Hemodynamic






              Serious infections                                  Diabetic Ketoacidosis





              Sepsis                                              Poisoning or overdose requiring

                                                                  close monitoring.



              Respiratory failure                                 People recovering from


                                                                  certain major surgeries
                                             14 I Page]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[PHARMACO




















                      V I G I L A N C E
















       Promote awareness                     Assessment of potential &                     Identify risk


         among patients &                         adverse effects of                 Associated with use


            general public                         pharmaceuticals                        of medicines





                                                                                        Promote safe,

        Identify and report                      Enhance patients                   effective & rotational


     adverse drug reactions                       safety & care in                          usage of


                 (ADRs)                        relation to medicines                   pharmaceuticals
                                                          use























                                                        15 I Page]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Pharmacogenomics is the study of how genes affect a person’s response to drugs. This field combines

         pharmacology (the science of drugs) and genomics (the study of genes and their functions) to develop

         effective, safe medications that can be prescribed based on a person’s genetic properties. The field of
           pharmacogenomics is growing, and new approaches are under study in clinical trials. In the future,

           pharmacogenomics will be used to develop tailored drugs to treat a wide range of health problems,

                        including cardiovascular disease, Alzheimer's disease, cancer, and asthma.









































      Telepharmacy is the delivery of pharmaceutical care via telecommunications to patients in locations where
          they may not have direct contact with a pharmacist. It is an instance of the wider phenomenon of

          telemedicine, as implemented in the field of pharmacy. . Telepharmacies improve drug-dispensing

         practices, including lower rates of medication dispensing errors. Pharmacists don't have a risk of viral

       transmission when consulting with patients. Clinical pharmacy specialists can provide patient counseling,
                          consultations and real- time monitoring to a wider range of patients










                                                        16 I Page]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[17 I Page]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Solid Organ Transplantation
      Solid Organ Transplantation













              Pharmacists play an important role in adjusting the use of antibiotics,


     anticoagulants, and antiarrhythmics by patients receiving a ventricular assist device

     (VAD). During HTx surgery and post-HTx, pharmacists advise physicians regarding


         the individualized medication protocol for immunosuppression and infection


             prevention to be used for each patient based on the patient’s pre-HTx

      characteristics as well as gene polymorphisms. They thus contribute to reducing


        the burden on the physician through the sharing of tasks. Throughout all three

                                                   phases of HTx,.



















                                                        18 I Page]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[IV ADMIXTURE-TDM
































                    Injectable drugs are the pharmaceutical preparation most frequently given


                      to hospitalized patients around the world. Injectable drugs can be given

                         alone or in the form of a mixture with other parenteral preparations.

                        Intravenous (i.v) admixtures are the mixing of two or more parenteral


                    preparations in a hospital to meet an individual patient´s therapeutic needs.

                      The mixing process of parenteral preparations is a complex process with


                                  various risks that arise if it is not prepared aseptically.


















                                                               19 I Page]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Psychiatric pharmacy, also known as mental health pharmacy, is the area of clinical


       pharmacy specializing in the treatment of people with psychiatric illnesses through

       the use of psychotropic medications. It is a branch of neuropsychiatric pharmacy,


     which includes neurologic pharmacy. Areas where psychiatric pharmacists are found

       most abundantly are in chemical dependency, developmental disabilities, long-term

       care facilities, adherence clinics, mental health clinics, and within the prison system.








                                      Switching your mindset from




                                                      “ I can't ” to


                                              “ I’ll learn" is life-changing.




                                                         20 I Page]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[It can be regarded as a branch of health economics

   which deals with identifying, measuring, and comparing


        the costs and consequences of pharmaceutical

   products and services. It helps in forming an economic


      relationship which combines the drug research, its

        production and distribution, storage, pricing, and


       further use by the people. Some of the concepts

     involved in pharmacoeconomic analysis include cost

   minimization, cost effectiveness, cost benefit, and cost


                              utility analysis.

















       They're experts on medications designed for patients

        with, or at risk for, cardiovascular disease. As such,


      they work as an integral part of a healthcare team and

        are involved in all aspects of cardiac care including

             heart transplants, artificial heart pumps, and


                anticoagulation (blood clot prevention).






















                                                         21 I Page]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[A bioavailability center in pharmacy focuses on studying and enhancing the


          bioavailability of drugs, which is the degree and rate at which an administered

         drug is absorbed into the systemic circulation, reaching the site of action. This

               center conducts research, development, and testing to optimize drug


        formulations and delivery methods, ensuring that medications are as effective as

                                                      possible.

















         Coding systems are important tools for the documentation of drug-related problems and

          following interventions. They should be suitable not only for scientific studies but for the

            broader implementation of Pharmaceutical Care in the pharmacy. A suitable coding

            system must be easy to use in daily routine. To facilitate later computer aided use, it

               should be preferably structured like a decision tree and consist of three parts:

                                   1. The classification of drug-related problems

                                   2. The intervention taken to solve to problem.

                                 3. The degree to which the problem was solved.


























                                                         22 I Page]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[ONCOLOGY






                                                PHARMACY








         An oncology pharmacist has a number of roles to fill. They usually work specifically in the administration of medicines to cancer
       patients in their treatment plans. They use their judgment in the dispensation of these medicines, An oncology pharmacist can also
           check on patients to see how the medicines are working. Ultimately, they are responsible for the recommendation, design,

        implementation, monitoring and modification of plans to treat patients with terminal diseases. They are viewed as an authoritative
                                source on the best uses of medications that treat individuals with cancer



































                                                         23 I Page]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Medical Writing is the translation of Science into Clear and


       Compelling Communication. Medical writing plays a critical

        role in the world of healthcare and medical research. It is


      the process of translating complex scientific information into

        clear, concise, and compelling communication that can be


        understood by a wide range of audiences, from scientists

         and healthcare professionals to patients and the general

                                         public.


















             It is called drug information, medication information, or drug informatics. It's really the

          discovery, use, and management of information in the use of medications. Drug information

           covers the gamut from identification, cost, and pharmacokinetics to dosage and adverse

                                                          effects.































                                                         24 I Page]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[In a world of medicine, be the







                                  dose of kindness.]]></page></pages></Search>