<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="58"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Faculty of Health



        Science Technology



          - Mansoura National



                       University








          Under Patronage of




        University President



            Prof. sherif Khater









         CONTACT US







           hscitechfac@mansnu.edu.eg









                editor in chief


     prof. Rasha M. Fathy Barea





                      vol. 1- Issue 1]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Table of Content







       1. Opening page                                                                                        1




       1.1 University President’s Speech                                                                      3




       1.2 Faculty Dean’ Speech                                                                               4




       2. About Faculty                                                                                       5




       3. Staff members                                                                                       9




       4. Events
                                                                                                             11





       5. Faculty achievements and activities
                                                                                                             21





       6. Student Honor board                                                                                30




       7. Social Events
                                                                                                             33





       8. Exclusive Encounters
                                                                                                             40





       9. Staff achievement                                                                                  42




       10. Academic and career advice                                                                        47




       11. Technical and scientific reviews                                                                  50




       12. Editorial board and Special thanks                                                                53]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[University President

                                                                                Prof. Cherif Khater

                                                                    Prof. Cherif Khater














                           University President’s Speech



                             Dear Health Sciences Technology Community,

     I am delighted to share with you the launch of the first issue of the Faculty of

     Health Sciences Technology magazine, a window that reflects the pulse of the
     faculty, its achievements, and its aspirations toward excellence and innovation.

     The establishment of this faculty represents a genuine addition to the university
     education system, as it offers modern programs that meet the needs of the job

     market in the health sector and contribute to preparing specialized scientific and

     health professionals equipped with knowledge, skills, and professional values.
     I also affirm my full support for this ambitious academic entity and for everything

     that can elevate the educational and research process while strengthening the

     university’s connection with the community.
     I  extend  my  heartfelt  thanks  to  the  Newsletter  team  for  this  wonderful  effort,

     wishing them continued success and prosperity.


                                                     Sincerely,



     Prof. Cherif Khater

     University President]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Dr. Rasha


    M. Fathy





    Dean of the Faculty of Health
    Sciences Technology








                                     Faculty Dean’ Speech



                                               Dear Colleagues,

    We  proudly  launch  today  the  first  issue  of  the  Faculty  of  Health  Sciences

    Technology  magazine,  through  which  we  aim  to  document  our  academic  and
    student  journey,  showcase  our  activities  and  achievements,  and  exchange

    experiences among members of the academic community.

    We embarked on this journey with a clear vision and a mission we take pride in,
    working tirelessly to build an academic entity that contributes to advancing the

    health  sector  in  Egypt  by  preparing  graduates  who  are  academically  and

    professionally qualified at the highest standards of quality.
    This  Newsletter  serves  as  a  mirror  reflecting  the  spirit  of  the  faculty,  its

    ambitions, and its community engagement, as well as a platform that highlights
    the  efforts  of  faculty  members,  the  excellence  of  students,  and  their

    participation in all activities.

    I  invite  everyone  to  contribute  to  this  collective  effort  to  develop  its  content,
    expand the horizons of collaboration, and make this Newsletter a distinguished

    scientific and cultural platform.


                                               Best regards,
    Prof. Dr. Rasha M. Fathy


    Dean of the Faculty of Health Sciences Technology]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[ABOUT FACULTY]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[About Faculty


     Mansoura National University is one of the pioneering and ambitious universities that is keen
     on  introducing  new  faculties  and  academic  programs  aligned  with  the  rapidly  evolving
     demands of the labor market. In light of the fast-paced developments in health informatics
     and  recent  advancements  in  healthcare  education,  the  development  of  health  education
     programs has become an urgent necessity to keep pace with these changes.

     Health Science Technology programs, in particular, have seen a growing demand in the job
     market  due  to  emerging  challenges  in  the  healthcare  sector.  The  university  offers  four
     distinguished programs designed to enrich the workforce with highly qualified graduates in
     the following areas:


            Medical Laboratory Sciences

            Radiologic Technology


           Health Statistics and Medical Informatics


           Emergency and Critical Care Technology







                      Vision



                     A leading and inspiring university educational institution that contributes to enriching the
                     future  through  leadership  in  education  and  scientific  research,  both  locally  and
                     internationally,  and  by  advancing  community  health  services  in  line  with  Egypt's  Vision
                     2030.







                     Mission

                     The  Faculty  of  Health  Sciences  Technology,  Mansoura  University,  seeks  to  provide
                     distinguished academic education and practical training based on scientific foundations
                     and high professional and ethical standards in a technological environment that supports
                     creativity  and  innovation.  The  aim  is  to  prepare  qualified  cadres  capable  of  continuous
                     development to meet the needs of the labor market, provide innovative scientific research,
                     and contribute to serving the community and improving the quality of health care in order
                     to achieve the goals of sustainable development.





                      General specifications for a graduate of the College of Health
                      Sciences Technology

                     Graduates from the Faculty of Health Science Technology will:
                        Proficient in specialized technological skills to improve the efficiency of health services under
                        the supervision of a physician.
                        Able to self-learn and motivated for continuous learning.
                        Familiar with the basics of scientific research and committed to its ethics
                        Respecting professional ethics and legal aspects.
                        Commit to quality standards.
                        Able to work in a successful team.]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Strategic Objectives

              1. Preparing specialized cadres through distinguished academic programs that keep pace with the latest
                scientific and technological developments
              2. Improving and developing education and learning systems by creating and maintaining an educational
                environment  that  fosters  creativity  and  raises  the  quality  and  efficiency  of  the  teaching  and  learning
                process.
              3. Supporting scientific and innovative research to contribute to improving health practices
              4. Providing  training  programs  and  workshops  that  build  students’  professional  competencies  which

                qualifies them to provide professional services efficiently and professionally.
              5. Contributing to improving health services by preparing specialized cadres who contribute to meeting the
                health care needs of the community
              6. Establishing  partnerships  with  hospitals,  health  and  educational  institutions  to  support  continuous
                development in the field of health sciences.
              7. Enhancing the use of artificial intelligence and technological technologies in diagnostic and educational
                services







                Program graduate specifications






                                         1. Medical laboratories program




                                          Graduate specifications:
                                          A  health  technologist  with  a  comprehensive  academic  background,  modern
                                          health knowledge and trends that keep pace with the development of the labor
                                          market in the health field of medical laboratory technology, and equipped with
                                          scientific  and  practical  skills  capable  of  preparing  and  processing  medical
                                          samples  in  most  forms  with  accuracy  and  speed,  able  to  operate  medical
                                          analysis  equipment  under  the  supervision  and  follow-up  of  a  specialist
                                          laboratory physician, and familiar with the procedures for periodic maintenance
                                          of equipment within the laboratory in accordance with quality and accreditation
                                          standards in healthcare facilities, while taking into account occupational safety
                                          for himself and the patient.





                                        2. Radiology Techniques Program




                                          Graduate specifications:
                                           A health technologist with a comprehensive academic background, including
                                          modern health knowledge and trends that keep pace with the development of
                                          the  labor  market  in  the  healthcare  field,  especially  radiology  and  medical
                                          imaging technology. He is trained on all diagnostic and therapeutic radiology
                                          equipment, familiar with the physical laws of radiation and its risks, and capable
                                          of  handling  all  types  of  radiology  equipment  under  the  supervision  of  a
                                          specialist radiologist, in accordance with quality and accreditation standards in
                                          healthcare  facilities,  while  taking  into  account  occupational  safety  for  himself
                                          and the patient.]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[3. Statistics and Medical
                                           Information Systems Program





                                          Graduate specifications
                                           A health technologist with a comprehensive academic background in modern
                                          health knowledge and trends that keep pace with the development of the labor
                                          market in the health sector, especially in the field of statistical technology and
                                          medical  information.  He  is  trained  in  the  use  of  statistics  to  analyze  the
                                          necessary medical data and modern technological systems for data collection in
                                          accordance with quality and accreditation standards in health facilities, with the
                                          foundations of occupational safety









                                         4. Critical and Emergency Medical
                                                         Care Program




                                          Graduate specifications:
                                           A health technologist with a comprehensive academic background, including
                                          modern health knowledge and trends that keep pace with the development of
                                          the labor market in the health sector, especially in critical and urgent medical
                                          care  technology.  He  is  familiar  with  the  basics  of  dealing  with  equipment  in
                                          intensive  care  rooms,  the  basics  of  resuscitation  and  early  detection  of
                                          complications, and is capable of dealing with patients on respiratory devices in
                                          critical urgent care under the supervision and direct instructions of a physician,
                                          in accordance with quality and accreditation standards in health facilities, while
                                          taking into account the principles of occupational safety for him and the patient.






                                             Studentst



                                             Activitities in this year]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[STAFF MEMBERS]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[staff members














                  Prof. Rasha Fathy Barwa                                 Prof. Areej Mostafa El-mahdy                          Manar Ahmed Nader El-Sayed
                  Dean of Faculty of health science                       Co-coordinator of the quality assurance                Professor and
                  technology                                              unite and academic guidance of Faculty of              head of Pharmacology & Toxicology
                                                                          health science technology


                                Asmaa Ibrahem                                            Ahmed Ramadan                                         Eman Mohammed Anwar EL-
                                Abo Seada                                                Abdelfattah el-Sheakh                                 Gendy
                                Assistant professor                                      Associate Professor                                   Associate Professor Computer
                                Critical Care Nursing Department                         Pharmacology and Toxicology                            and System Engineering
                                                                                                                                               Department

                   Mona Ahmed Sameeh Ragii Fouda                          Nermin Ali Abd El-hakim Ali                            Enas El Sayed Mohamed Abdelrahman
                   Assistant Professor                                    Lecturer                                               Lecturer
                   Department of Mathematics                              Physics Department                                     Department of English


                                                                                                                                                Rehab Hamadtoh
                                Dr. Ibrahim Attia Al-Mahdi                              Omar Wahba                                              AbulGhait Gohar
                                Lecturer                                                Teaching Assistant                                      Associate professor of
                                General law Department                                  Computer and System Engineering                         curriculum & instruction
                                                                                        Department


                   Ahmed Samir Ahmed Gardouh                              Aamal gamal el-din el-waseif                           Esraa gamal el-din el-waseif
                   Assistant Lecturer                                     Assistant lecturer                                     Assistant lecturer
                   Electrical Department                                  Pharmacology and toxicology department                 Pharmacology and toxicology department



                                                                                       Ali Azab Elsayed Ali                                    Ahmed Akram Ali Ghanem
                                Mohamed El-Saied Mohamed Sanad
                                                                                       Demonstrator                                            Demonstrator
                                Demonstrator
                                Physics Department                                     Electrical Power                                        Department of Mathematics &
                                                                                       Engineering Department                                  Engineering Physics

                   Zuhir Magdy                                           Yaser Ahmed                                              Habiba mohamed abdelaziz
                   Demonstrator                                          Demonstrator Electrical Power                            Demonstrator Pharmacology
                   Physics Department                                    Engineering Department                                   and toxicology department]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[staff members














 Prof. Rasha Fathy Barwa  Prof. Areej Mostafa El-mahdy  Manar Ahmed Nader El-Sayed
 Dean of Faculty of health science  Co-coordinator of the quality assurance  Professor and
 technology  unite and academic guidance of Faculty of  head of Pharmacology & Toxicology
 health science technology


 Asmaa Ibrahem  Ahmed Ramadan                              Eman Mohammed Anwar EL-
 Abo Seada  Abdelfattah el-Sheakh                          Gendy
 Assistant professor  Associate Professor                  Associate Professor Computer
 Critical Care Nursing Department  Pharmacology and Toxicology   and System Engineering
                                                           Department

 Mona Ahmed Sameeh Ragii Fouda  Nermin Ali Abd El-hakim Ali  Enas El Sayed Mohamed Abdelrahman
 Assistant Professor  Lecturer               Lecturer
 Department of Mathematics   Physics Department  Department of English


                                                            Rehab Hamadtoh
 Dr. Ibrahim Attia Al-Mahdi  Omar Wahba                     AbulGhait Gohar
 Lecturer  Teaching Assistant                               Associate professor of
 General law Department  Computer and System Engineering    curriculum & instruction
    Department


 Ahmed Samir Ahmed Gardouh  Aamal gamal el-din el-waseif  Esraa gamal el-din el-waseif
 Assistant Lecturer  Assistant lecturer      Assistant lecturer
 Electrical Department   Pharmacology and toxicology department  Pharmacology and toxicology department



   Ali Azab Elsayed Ali                                    Ahmed Akram Ali Ghanem
 Mohamed El-Saied Mohamed Sanad
   Demonstrator                                            Demonstrator
 Demonstrator
 Physics Department  Electrical Power                      Department of Mathematics &
   Engineering Department                                  Engineering Physics

 Zuhir Magdy  Yaser Ahmed                     Habiba mohamed abdelaziz
 Demonstrator  Demonstrator Electrical Power  Demonstrator Pharmacology
 Physics Department  Engineering Department   and toxicology department]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[EVENTS]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[SEMINAR TITLED "STEPS TO UNIVERSITY SUCCESS”
















































































      In line with Mansoura University's commitment to supporting its students and guiding them toward
      academic excellence, and under the patronage of Prof. Dr. Sherif Khater, President of the University, and
      the leadership of Prof. Dr. Rasha Barwa, Dean of the Faculty of Health Sciences Technology, the Faculty
      of Health Sciences Technology organized an awareness seminar titled "Steps to University Success" on
      Saturday, October 12. Prof. Dr. Rasha Barwa addressed a number of important topics, most notably the
      concept of university success and the keys to excellence in the first year of study. She also emphasized
      the importance of engaging in diverse university activities in discovering and developing talents.]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[IMPORTANCE OF STUDENT ACTIVITIES









































































    On Saturday morning, October 19, the Faculty of Health Sciences Technology at the university organized an
    introductory seminar titled "The Importance of Student Activities in University Life." The seminar aimed
    On Saturday morning, October 19, the Faculty of Health Sciences Technology at the university organized anto raise
    students' awareness of the role of student activities in developing their skills and refining their personalities,
    introductory seminar titled "The Importance of Student Activities in University Life." The seminar aimed to raise
    and to encourage them to engage in available activities for a comprehensive university experience.
    students' awareness of the role of student activities in developing their skills and refining their personalities, and to
    encourage them to engage in available activities for a comprehensive university experience.
    In her opening remarks, Prof. Rasha Barwa, Dean of the College, emphasized the importance of student
    In her opening remarks, Prof. Rasha Barwa, Dean of the College, emphasized the importance of student activities in
    activities in building students' character and enhancing communication and teamwork skills. Following this, Mr.
    building students' character and enhancing communication and teamwork skills. Following this, Mr. Hassan Abu Al-
    Hassan Abu Al-Wafa, Student Activities Officer at the university, gave a comprehensive presentation on the
    Wafa, Student Activities Officer at the university, gave a comprehensive presentation on the Student Union and its
    Student Union and its various committees, explaining the roles each committee plays in serving the student
    various committees, explaining the roles each committee plays in serving the student community. He also reviewed
    community. He also reviewed the procedures for running for the union elections, both at the college and
    the procedures for running for the union elections, both at the college and university levels, with the aim of
    university levels, with the aim of motivating students to actively participate in decision-making that concerns
    motivating students to actively participate in decision-making that concerns them.
    them.]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[CLINICAL IMAGING GUIDELINES: CHOOSE WISELY AND SAFELY


                      PROVIDED BY SAUDI GERMAN HOSPITAL – ALEXANDRIA




























































     Students from the Faculty of Health Sciences Technology participated in the "Clinical Imaging

      Guidelines" conference, held on Thursday, October 31, at the Saudi German Hospital in Borg
      El Arab. The conference aimed to enhance communication between students and the latest
                        developments in medical imaging and healthcare technology
       The conference included a series of scientific lectures covering topics in nuclear medicine

          and radiation safety, including "Safety in Nuclear Medicine," "Quality in the Radiology
        Department," and "Artificial Intelligence and Radiation Safety." It also included advanced
     sessions on "Imaging Techniques and Methods." These lectures were delivered by a group of
       experts and specialists in the field of radiology, who reviewed the latest technologies and

                                                     professional
      practices that ensure safe and effective service In addition, students had the opportunity to
     tour the radiology departments at the Saudi German Hospital, where they were introduced to
     the latest radiology and medical imaging technologies, with the aim of familiarizing students

                       with the latest equipment and devices used in medical imaging]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[PROTECTION FROM INFECTION

































































      In line with the goals of the presidential initiative "A New Beginning for Building the Egyptian

       Human Being," and as #Mansoura_University strives to enhance student health awareness
      and spread health culture within the community, the Faculty of Health Sciences Technology
     organized an awareness seminar titled "Protection from Infection" on Saturday, December 7.
         The seminar was held under the patronage of Professor Sherif Khater, President of the

                     University, and led by Professor Rasha Barwa, Dean of the Faculty.
      The seminar addressed several important topics, including the definition and importance of
      infection control, methods of its spread, and various types of infections, including hospital-
           acquired infections. During the seminar, Dr. Mahasen Obeya, a fellow at Mansoura

      University's Internal Medicine Specialized Hospital and a certified trainer from the Supreme
     Council of Universities, explained infection prevention equipment and how to use it. She also
          raised awareness of the correct method of handwashing as a key element in reducing
                                               infection transmission.]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[THE PAST AND THE PRESENT AND THE LESSONS LEARNED































































     As part of Mansoura Private University's celebrations of the 51st anniversary of the glorious October
      victories, and under the auspices of Prof. Dr. Sherif Youssef Khater, President of the University, the
        university organized a symposium entitled "Between the Past and the Present and the Lessons
     Learned", on Wednesday, October 30. Prof. Dr. Sherif Youssef Khater, President of the University, and
        Prof. Dr. Mohamed Abdel Azim, Engineering Advisor to the President of the University, received
       Major General Pilot Ahmed Kamal El Mansouri, one of the heroes of the Egyptian Air Force in the
         October War, in the presence of Prof. Dr. Rasha Barwa, Dean of the Faculty of Health Sciences
                                                      Technology.
      In his speech, Professor Sherif Khater highlighted the importance of the October War victory, which
     represents a symbol of pride and determination. He emphasized that this great anniversary embodies

     an example to be emulated at the national and international levels. He explained that the Egyptian Air
      Force played a pivotal role in achieving victory, leading a devastating air strike that targeted enemy
           positions with precision and unwavering resolve. This strike was the spark that ignited the
       enthusiasm of the soldiers and raised their morale in battle. It laid the foundation for subsequent
     victories that restored Egypt's land and dignity. He added, "The first air strike will remain a testament
       to the courage of the Egyptian pilots, who proved to the world that Egypt is capable of overcoming
                                    any challenge with the help of its loyal sons.]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[HOW TO PREPARE FOR EXAMS










































































    In a bid to provide the necessary support to its students and enhance their readiness for the final exams of the
    On Saturday morning, October 19, the Faculty of Health Sciences Technology at the university organized an
    first semester, and under the patronage of Professor Dr. Sherif Khater, President of the University, Professor
    introductory seminar titled "The Importance of Student Activities in University Life." The seminar aimed to raise
    Dr. Rasha Barwa, Dean of the Faculty of Health Sciences Technology, held a meeting with first-year students on
    students' awareness of the role of student activities in developing their skills and refining their personalities, and to
    Saturday, December 14. During the meeting, she emphasized the importance of this first stage in their
    encourage them to engage in available activities for a comprehensive university experience.
    university life, as it is the cornerstone of their academic and professional future.
    In her opening remarks, Prof. Rasha Barwa, Dean of the College, emphasized the importance of student activities in
    She also emphasized that exams are not merely a test of knowledge, but rather an opportunity to demonstrate
    building students' character and enhancing communication and teamwork skills. Following this, Mr. Hassan Abu Al-
    the effort and continuous work they have put in throughout the semester. She also offered advice to students,
    Wafa, Student Activities Officer at the university, gave a comprehensive presentation on the Student Union and its
    including how to manage their time while preparing for exams, noting the importance of organizing a review
    various committees, explaining the roles each committee plays in serving the student community. He also reviewed
    schedule to achieve a balance between studying and rest, which helps maintain focus and optimal preparation.
    the procedures for running for the union elections, both at the college and university levels, with the aim of
    She also emphasized adherence to the instructions issued by the faculty administration to ensure the smooth
    motivating students to actively participate in decision-making that concerns them.
    running of exams.]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[FACULTY














                      ACHIEVEMENTS















                   AND ACTIVITIES]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[PRESENTATIONS ON



                                         THE TOPIC OF UNIVERSITY LIFE

































































    On Sunday, November 17, the College of Health Sciences Technology organized an educational activity as part
    of the theoretical lessons for the English language course. The activity was held under the patronage of
    Professor Sherif Khater, President of the University, and under the leadership of Professor Rasha Barwa, Dean
    of the College, and the supervision of Dr. Rehab Abo El-Gheit and Dr. Enas Abdel Rahman, course instructors.
    The activity featured students giving presentations on the topic of university life, a pivotal stage in shaping
    their personalities and preparing them for university life. The presentations highlighted the importance of this
    stage in honing social communication skills through teamwork and openness to diverse cultures, in addition to
    enhancing independence by acquiring the ability to manage time and assume responsibilities. The
    presentations also addressed how to face academic and personal challenges and develop stress management
    skills.
    Dr. Rasha Barwa stated that this activity embodies the university's philosophy of supporting interactive
    learning, where students become active partners in the learning process rather than merely recipients of
    information]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[PRACTICAL APPLICATION



                                  OF THE RECIPROCAL TEACHING STRATEGY





































































    In line with Mansoura Private University's commitment to developing the educational process and enhancing
    the capabilities of its students, the university is under the patronage of Professor Dr. Sherif Khater, President
    of the University, the leadership of Professor Dr. Rasha Barwa, Dean of the Faculty, and the supervision of Dr.
    Narmin Abdel Hakim, Professor of Fundamentals of Physics. On Tuesday, November 26, the College of Health
    Sciences Technology witnessed a practical application of the Reciprocal Teaching Strategy, an educational
    strategy aimed at enhancing students' cognitive skills and interactive abilities. Students explained part of a
    lecture on fluid mechanics within the Fundamentals of Physics course, allowing them to apply the methods of
    this strategy in practice. This demonstrated their ability to absorb the material and present it interactively,
    contributing to strengthening students' personalities and developing their cognitive and interactive abilities]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[WEEK FOR PHYSICS



                                        AND ITS MEDICAL APPLICATION




































































    In line with Mansoura University's commitment to providing integrated education that combines academic and
    practical aspects, and its commitment to enabling its students to expand their horizons and acquire new skills
    beyond traditional education, the Faculty of Health Sciences Technology concluded the Scientific Week on
    Physics and its Medical Applications, which was held from December 5 to 11. The event was held under the
    patronage of Professor Sherif Khater, President of the University, and under the leadership of Professor Rasha
    Mohamed Fathy, Dean of the Faculty, and under the supervision of Dr. Nermin Abd El-Hakim, Dr. Mohamed
    Sand, and Dr. Zuhair Magdy, faculty members.
    The Scientific Week addressed the topic of medical physics and its role in modern healthcare, as well as its
    importance in enabling doctors to provide accurate diagnoses and effective treatment using advanced
    technologies, which positively impacts patient health.]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Educational activity on Artificial Intelligence



                                                    in medical fields













                 Vision         Vision                              Vision  Vision
                   Vision

















                              Vision






























   In an effort by #Mansoura_University to empower its students to acquire new skills and

   expand their horizons beyond traditional education, the event was held under the
   patronage of Professor Dr. Sherif Khater, President of the University, under the leadership
   of Professor Dr. Rasha Mohamed Fathy, Dean of the Faculty of Health Sciences Technology,
   and under the supervision of Dr. Iman El-Gendy, Engineer Yasser Abdel Nabi, Engineer Omar
   Wahba, and Engineer Ali Azab.
   The Faculty of Health Sciences Technology organized an educational activity on Sunday
   and Thursday, December 8 and 12. The activity included presentations by student groups
                                              Vision
                                       Vision
   within the Computer Skills course. The presentations focused on the use of artificial
   intelligence in medical fields and aimed to introduce students to the pivotal role of artificial
   intelligence in medicine and how it can be used to support doctors in diagnosis and
   treatment decisions.]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[FUN AND LEARNING

















































































    The College of Health Sciences Technology organized a fun day on Thursday morning, December 12, under the
    patronage of Professor Sherif Khater, President of the University, and led by Professor Rasha Barwa, Dean of
    the College.
    The day, held under the theme "Fun and Learning," included a variety of activities that combined entertainment
    and education. The day featured quiz competitions, which were met with student interaction, demonstrating a
    spirit of challenge and creative thinking. Activities such as colorful games added a lively and joyful
    atmosphere, as well as a variety of sports and recreational competitions that fostered a spirit of cooperation
    and teamwork among students.]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Ping Pong and


                                             chess sports competition













               Vision        Vision
              Vision                                                 Vision  Vision





















































     The Faculty of Health Sciences Technology organized a sports competition for students in
     table tennis and chess on Saturday, December 14, in cooperation with the Faculty Student
     Union. The competition witnessed wide participation from students, who competed for top
     places in a competitive atmosphere. Representatives of the Student Union were also
     present, along with a large number of students who were keen to encourage their fellow
     competitors.
     The results of the competition resulted in Nour El-Din Mahmoud winning first place, and
                                              Vision
                                       Vision
     Youssef Abu El-Mati winning second place in the table tennis championship (boys), while
     Mena Allah Mohamed Mustafa won the table tennis championship (girls).
     Student Mohamed Marwan Mohamed also won first place, while student Youssef Sabry
     Ibrahim won second place in the boys' chess championship. Student Heba Tariq Sayed
     Ahmed won first place in the girls' chess championship.]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[Organizing an ArtExhibition













                 Vision                                                    Vision
                   Vision       Vision                              Vision
















                              Vision































       On Tuesday, December 17, the Faculty of Health Sciences Technology organized an art
       exhibition in cooperation with the Faculty's Student Union. The exhibition saw the wide
      participation of talented students, who presented a variety of innovative artworks. The
         exhibits included paintings using various techniques, such as watercolor and pencil
           drawing, as well as handicrafts and innovative designs using recycled materials.
      Dr. Rasha Barwa emphasized that the exhibition aims to showcase students' talents and
       encourage them to express themselves through art, in addition to fostering a spirit of
     innovation and communication among them. She added that the Faculty always strives to
     support activities that develop students' creative skills and provide them with a space to
                                                express their ideas.
                                              Vision
    The exhibition was well-received by students, who expressed their admiration for the level
                                       Vision
    of creativity and diversity in the artwork. A competition was held to evaluate the displayed
      works, with attendees voting for the best participating works. Rawan Hamada Ahmed, a
    student in the College of Health Sciences Technology, won first place for her artwork in the
                                                      exhibition]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[Day of educational activities














               Vision         Vision                                Vision  Vision
                Vision
















                            Vision































     As part of Mansoura University's ongoing efforts to empower its students to broaden their
      horizons and acquire practical skills beyond traditional education, the Faculty of Health
       Sciences Technology organized the second day of educational activities related to the

                             theoretical lessons of the English language course.
        The event was held under the patronage of Professor Sherif Khater, President of the
        University, and under the leadership of Professor Rasha Mohamed Fathy, Dean of the
      Faculty, and under the supervision of Dr. Rehab Aboul Gheit and Dr. Enas Abdel Rahman,
     English language course professors. During the day, students gave several presentations
       on various topics, such as the impact of social media on society, healthy eating habits,
         cancer, university life, and other topics. The goal was to enhance students' English
                                              Vision
                                       Vision
      communication skills. This allows them to practice the language in practical and real-life
      contexts, which helps improve pronunciation, vocabulary selection, and fluency. These
    activities contribute to developing self-confidence through speaking confidently in front of
       an audience, enhancing presentation skills and the ability to express ideas clearly and
                                                       logically.]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[STUDENT HONOR














                                           BOARD]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[Top Ranked




                                              Students



                              For the first semester 2024/2025







        1                       2                              3                             4











                                     Menna alaah kamal            Nour Mohamed                  Sara Mohamed
            Samaa Ahmed                   shawkie
               elsaeed                                           Abdelgwad Elbaz                 Fathy Elbaz



      4                              5                          6                          7










           Sohaila Ebrahim             Abrar Wael Ezat              Haneen Nazeh
           Hamed Esmaeil                 Mohammed                    Abdelhafez                  Omnia Hamdy
              Elshamy                    Elaqabawy                   Abdelwahab               Mohammed Kassab


      7                            8                            8                            8











       Eman Gaber Ahmed               Basmala Mohamed                Radwa Hassan
        Mohammed Abu Al-               fakieh Mohamed              Ahmed Abualfutuh              Salma Waleed
              Sayed                                                                          Mohamed Mohamed EL
                                                                                                    Sihemy



         8                            9                        10                            10











          Nagham El-dosouqy            Naglaa ebrahim             Thoraya Nabil Galal             Habiba Elsepaey
               Mostafa.                sobhi abdelgani                                               Mohamed]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[Students




                                                   Union






















                                                                                      Abdelrahman Elaraby
                    Esam Atef                                                           Secretary of Artistic
                 Assistant Secretary of                                                     Committee
                the Scouting Committee                          Shorouk Hossam
                                        Naglaa Ebrahim           Assistant Secretary of
                                          Assistant Secretary of   Trips Committee
                                          Scientific Committee















        Mai magdy                                                                              Eman Mohammed

       Secretary of  Trips                                                                          Secretary of
          Committee                                                      Mohammad Sameh          Scientific committee
                                                    Shorouk Ahmed
                               Rahma abdo             Vice President of   Secretary of Unions and
                              President of  Faculty  Faculty Student Union  Families Committee
                                 Student Union


















                                                                                       Rahma elsaed
              youssef Ayman                                                            Secretary of  Cultural
                  Secretary of the                                                         Committee
                Scouting Committee                              Shahd Mohamed
                                      youssef shaaban            Assistant Secretary of
                                          Secretary of Sports     Cultural Committee
                                             Committee]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[SOCIAL EVENTS]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[Opening  Faculty




      On Saturday, September 28, 2024, the Faculty of Health Sciences Technology at
      Mansoura National University officially launched its welcoming activities for the
      first-ever student cohort of the 2024/2025 academic year.

       The event was held under the patronage of Prof. Dr. Sherif Youssef Khater,
      University President, and led by Prof. Dr. Rasha Mohamed Fathy, Dean of the
      Faculty, with the presence of many esteemed faculty members and teaching
      assistants.

       The celebration marked a vibrant and inspiring start for new students as they
      embarked on their academic journey in the health sciences field.










              Vision                                                 Vision  Vision
               Vision        Vision





















                             Vision




























                                       Vision  Vision]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[Celebrating Student Champions



















                              Vision


















       On December 21, the Faculty of Health Sciences Technology at Mansoura

       University National honored the winners of the chess and table tennis
       competitions. Under the patronage of Prof. Dr. Sherif Khater and the leadership
       of Prof. Dr. Rasha Barwa, students were celebrated for their skill, sportsmanship,
       and competitive spirit. The event highlighted the faculty's commitment to
       nurturing talent both academically and beyond.



                        Honoring Creative Talents





























       On  Saturday,  December  21,  the  Faculty  of  Health  Sciences  Technology  at
       Mansoura  University  National  held  a  special  ceremony  to  honor  the  talented
       female students who participated in the art exhibition. Under the patronage of
       Prof.  Dr.  Sherif  Khater  and  the  leadership  of  Prof.  Dr.  Rasha  Fathy  Barwa,  the
       event celebrated the students' creativity and impressive artistic contributions,

       which showcased their unique talents across various art forms.]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[Outstanding Student Recognition



                medical Physics and Its Medical



                                  Applications Week


















                              Vision


































                            Vision

















      On  December  21,  the  Faculty  of  Health  Sciences  Technology  at  Mansoura
      University  National  honored  the  winners  of  the  chess  and  table  tennis
      competitions. Under the patronage of Prof. Dr. Sherif Khater and the leadership

      of Prof. Dr. Rasha Barwa, students were celebrated for their skill, sportsmanship,
      and  competitive  spirit.  The  event  highlighted  the  faculty's  commitment  to
      nurturing talent both academically and beyond.]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[Celebrating the End of Exams




     On Saturday, September 28, 2024, the Faculty of Health Sciences Technology
     at Mansoura National University officially launched its welcoming activities for

     the first-ever student cohort of the 2024/2025 academic year.
       The  event  was  held  under  the  patronage  of  Prof.  Dr.  Sherif  Youssef  Khater,

     University President, and led by Prof. Dr. Rasha Mohamed Fathy, Dean of the
     Faculty, with the presence of many esteemed faculty members and teaching

     assistants.
      The celebration marked a vibrant and inspiring start for new students as they

     embarked on their academic journey in the health sciences field.














               Vision                                                    Vision
                Vision



















                             Vision

                                                           ﻚﺗﺮﻘﻓ ﺺﻧ



























                                                     Vision]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[Celebrating Excellence Honoring



                                          Top Achievers




    On Wednesday, February 12, the Faculty of Health Sciences Technology at Mansoura
    National  University  held  a  special  ceremony  to  honor  top-performing  first-year
    students for their academic excellence in the first semester. Under the patronage of

    Prof.  Dr.  Sherif  Youssef  Khater,  University  President,  and  leadership  of  Prof.  Dr.
    Rasha Mohamed Fathy, Dean of the Faculty, the event was filled with pride and joy.
    Surrounded by Academic staff, families, and peers, students received certificates of
    appreciation in recognition of their hard work and dedication. Congratulations to all

    the honorees—we wish you continued success and achievement!
                      click here to go to Appreciation of students Top Achievers









             Vision             Vision                             Vision  Vision
                Vision






















                              Vision



























                                        Vision  Vision]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[Honoring Dedication



































              Vision
               Vision                                                Vision  Vision
                             Vision


     On  Wednesday,  December  25,  the  Faculty  of  Health  Sciences  Technology  at
     Mansoura University National held a special ceremony to honor Dr. Basma Mahmoud
     Hussein  for  her  outstanding  administrative  efforts  and  professional  dedication.
     Attended by colleagues and staff, the event recognized her vital role in advancing
     the  college’s  mission.  Dr.  Basma  expressed  her  gratitude,  emphasizing  that  true

     success comes through teamwork and commitment.







                              Behind Every Success:


                                  Our Academic staff






     This video expresses heartfelt appreciation to the dedicated teaching team of the
     Faculty  of  Health  Sciences  Technology  at  Mansoura  University  National.  Their
     continuous support, guidance, and hard work throughout the first semester played
     a vital role in shaping a successful academic journey for the students. Thank you for

     your commitment and excellence!



                         click here to go to Appreciation of Faculty staff member


                   click here to go to Appreciation of Faculty assistant staff member]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[EXCLUSIVE














                            ENCOUNTERS]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[Meeting of the committee




                                formulating the vision,



                                      mission and goals
















































  In  an  engaging  and  dynamic  virtual  meeting,  the  college’s  community  stakeholders  came

  together online in an exceptional session that brought together the Dean, the Director of the
  Quality Assurance Unit, the Quality Coordinator, an elite group of faculty members from various
  disciplines,  and  representatives  of  the  general  and  branch  unions.  The  goal  was  clear  and
  ambitious: to craft an inspiring vision, a mission reflecting the college’s identity, and strategic

  objectives  for  the  college  and  its  academic  programs.  Ideas  were  exchanged  openly  and
  creatively, blending expertise and insights to shape a distinguished academic future, enhancing
  quality and solidifying the college’s position as a beacon of knowledge and innovation.


                             Vision










                                     Vision  Vision]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[STAFF














                         ACHIEVEMENT]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[Prof. Rasha Fathy Barwa


                                                    Dean of Faculty of health science technology



                                                    Professor of Microbiology & Immunology

















            Rewards and Prizes                    Seminars and workshops                 Published research




            -Inspiring staff award from faculty of  -Steps to University success (speaker) 12  1- Characterization of non-O157
            pharmacy Mansoura National University  &15/10/2024                           enterohemorrhagic Escherichia coli
            -                                     at faculty of Health Science technology-  isolated from different sources in Egypt
            Honored by the Faculty of Pharmacy    Mansoura National University           Journal
            Council, Mansoura University, for     - Seminar on how to prepare for exams  BMC microbiology
            receiving the Best Course Award in the  )speakers) 14/12/2024 at faculty of Health  Volume
            fifth level of the Pharm D program    Science technology Mansoura National   24
            (Medical Microbiology) for the first  University                             Issue
            semester of 2023/2024.                - Protection from infection(attendance)  1
                                                  7/12/2024 at faculty of Health Science  https://link.springer.com/article/10.1186/s
            -Honored by the Faculty of Pharmacy   technology Mansoura National University  12866-024-03636-3
            Council, Mansoura University, for     -A symposium between the present and   2- Prevalence and antimicrobial
            receiving the Best Course Award in the  the future on the celebrations of the  susceptibility of Enterobacteriaceae
            fifth level of the Pharm D Clinical   victory of the October War  (attendance)  isolated from ready-to-eat foods retailed
            pharmacy program (Medical             30/10/2024 at Mansoura National        in Damietta, Egypt
            Microbiology) for the first semester of  University.                         Journal
            2023/2024.                                                                   Egyptian Journal of Basic and Applied
                                                                                         Sciences
                                                                                         Volume
                                                                                         11
                                                                                         Issue
                                                                                         1
                                                                                         https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.
                                                                                         1080/2314808X.2024.2307847#d1e243
                                  Conferences
                                                                                         7
                                                                                         3- Assessment of typing methods,
                                                                                         virulence genes profile and antimicrobial
                                                                                         susceptibility for clinical isolates of Proteus
                                  Clinical imaging guidelines: choose wisely             mirabilis
                                  and safely                                             Journal
                                  Provided by Saudi German Hospital –                    Annals of Clinical Microbiology and
                                  Alexandria in collaboration with the                   Antimicrobials
                                  Egyptian Society of Safety and Quality in              Volume
                                  Radiology and Clinical Imaging                         24
                                  31/10/2024                                             Issue
                                                                                         1
                                                                                         https://link.springer.com/article/10.1186/s
                                                                                         12941-024-00770-8]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[Prof. Areej Mostafa El-mahdy



                                                     Co-coordinator of the quality assurance unite and
                                                     academic guidance of Faculty of health science
                                                     technology

                                                     Professor of Microbiology & Immunology



                                                     -Program and institutional accreditation
                                                     standards (online 06/11/2024)









































                                                       Dr. Enas Elsayed Mohamed



                                                       Lecturer, department of English,
                                                        Faculty of Education, Mansoura University


                                                       -Attending online workshop from Egyptian
                                                       Knowledge Bank (EKB) entitled "Sage Unique

                                                       Content"]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[Dr. Nermin Ali Abdelhakim


                                                      Lecturer of Materials Physics













                   Conferences                                  Published research


                                                                1-Amal Abdallah El-Sherif, Nermin A.
                   1-The 9  scientific symposium on the role    Abdelhakim, Hamed Al-Sorory, Rizk
                        th
                   of chemistry in environmental challenges     Mostafa Shalaby," Effect of Composition
                   and sustainable development                  on Structural, Mechanical, and Wetting
                   achievement (2024), Hurghada, Egypt.         Properties of Sn-40Bi-xAg Lead-Free
                   2-The Symposium on German-MENA               Solder Alloys for Green Electronics",
                   Industry and Technology Exchange             Journal of Materials Engineering and
                   (2024), Mansoura University in               Performance (2024).
                   collaboration with DAAD, Egypt.              2-Asma S. Al-Wasidi1, Ehab A.
                                                                Abdelrahman, Reem K. Shah, Nermin A.
                                                                Abdelhakim, Fawaz A. Saad," Facile
                                                                synthesis of novel nanocomposite
                                                                composed of Co3O4, MgO, and
                                                                Mg3B2O6 for malachite green dye
                                                                decontamination from aqueous media",
                                                                Scientific Reports (2024).
                                                                3-Nermin A. Abdelhakim, Abdelmoneim
                                                                Saleh, M. Mitwalli, A. H. El-Farrash, Rizk
                                                                Mostafa Shalaby," A good balance
                                                                between the efficiency of ionizing
                                                                radiation shielding and mechanical
                                                                performance of various tin-based alloys:
                                                                Comparative analysis", Radiation Physics
                                                                and Chemistry (2024).
                                                                4-Nermin A. Abdelhakim, Osama M.
                                                                Hemeda, Rizk M. Shalaby and M Mostafa,
                                                                " The Role of Phase Transformation
                                                                (Tetragonal- Spinel) On the Structural and
                                                                Mechanical Properties of Ni Doped
                                                                CuFe O  ", Applied Physics A (2024).
                                                                     4
                                                                   2]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[Esraa Gamal El-din


                                             Assistant lecturer, Pharmacology and Toxicology
                                             department, Faculty of Pharmacy, Mansoura
                                             University.






                                             Conferences                               Seminars and workshops



                                                                                       -Attending a lecture from training and
                                             Attendance of conference entitled         research services office (TRSO) entitled
                                             "Clinical imaging guidelines: choose wisely  "reviewing a research article", Faculty of
                                             and safely", Saudi German Hospital, Alex  Pharmacy, Mansoura University on
                                             on 31/10/2024.                            24/11/2024.
                                                                                       -Attending a lecture from TRSO entitled
                                                                                       "Cancer immunotherapy and metabolism
                                                                                       – Checkpoint inhibitors" on 15/12/2024.
                                                                                       -Attendance of webinar from Egyptian
                                                                                       Knowledge Bank (EKB) entitled "The
                                                                                       selection criteria for international journals"
                                                                                       on 16/12/2024.
                                                                                       -Attending a lecture from TRSO entitled
                                                                                       "Cancer immunotherapy and metabolism
                                                                                       – Immunomodulating drugs" on
                                                                                       22/12/2024.











                                             Aamal Gamal El-din



                                             Assistant lecturer, Pharmacology and Toxicology
                                             department, Faculty of Pharmacy, Mansoura
                                             University.







                                             Conferences                               Seminars and workshops


                                                                                       -Attending a lecture from training and
                                             Attendance of conference entitled         research services office (TRSO) entitled
                                             "Clinical imaging guidelines: choose wisely  "reviewing a research article", Faculty of
                                             and safely", Saudi German Hospital, Alex  Pharmacy, Mansoura University on
                                             on 31/10/2024.                            24/11/2024.
                                                                                       -Attending a lecture from TRSO entitled
                                                                                       "Cancer immunotherapy and metabolism
                                                                                       – Checkpoint inhibitors" on 15/12/2024.
                                                                                       -Attendance of webinar from Egyptian
                                                                                       Knowledge Bank (EKB) entitled "The
                                                                                       selection criteria for international journals"
                                                                                       on 16/12/2024.
                                                                                       -Attending a lecture from TRSO entitled
                                                                                       "Cancer immunotherapy and metabolism
                                                                                       – Immunomodulating drugs" on
                                                                                       22/12/2024.]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[ACADEMIC AND














                     CAREER ADVICE]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[A. How to Succeed in Your Studies: Practical Tips

              for Academic Excellence ?


              Achieving  academic  excellence  requires  a  combination  of  effective  study
              habits, time management, and a positive mindset. Here are some practical tips
              to help you succeed in your studies:




              1. Set Clear Goals


              Achieving  academic  excellence  requires  a  combination  of  effective  study  habits,  time  management,
              and a positive mindset. Here are some practical tips to help you succeed in your studies:







              2. Create a Study Schedule

              Organize your time by creating a study schedule. Allocate specific time slots for studying, breaks, and
              other activities. Stick to your schedule to build a consistent study routine.







              3. Find a Suitable Study Environment

              Choose a quiet and comfortable place to study, free from distractions. A good study environment can
              improve your concentration and productivity.





              4. Take Effective Notes

              Develop a note-taking system that works for you. Summarize key points, use bullet points, and highlight
              important information. Reviewing your notes regularly can reinforce your learning.




              5. Use Active Learning Techniques


              Engage  with  the  material  actively  by  asking  questions,  discussing  with  peers,  and  teaching  others.
              Active learning helps deepen your understanding and retention of the subject matter




              6. Practice Time Management

              Prioritize  your  tasks  and  manage  your  time  effectively.  Break  down  large  assignments  into  smaller,
              manageable tasks and set deadlines for each. Avoid procrastination by starting tasks early.


               1. Stay organized by using a planner or digital calendar. Also, there are several great time management
                 applications that can help you stay organized and productive. Here are a few popular ones:       Ø
                 Clockify      Ø Notion   Ø ProofHub]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[A. How to Succeed in Your Studies: Practical Tips

              for Academic Excellence ?


              Achieving  academic  excellence  requires  a  combination  of  effective  study
              habits, time management, and a positive mindset. Here are some practical tips
              to help you succeed in your studies:




              7. Stay Organized


              Keep your study materials, notes, and assignments organized. Use folders, binders, or digital tools to
              keep track of your work. An organized workspace can reduce stress and save time.







              8. Take Care of Your Health

              Maintain a healthy lifestyle by eating nutritious food, getting regular exercise, and ensuring adequate
              sleep. A healthy body supports a healthy mind, which is essential for academic success.






              9. Seek Help When Needed

              Don't hesitate to ask for help if you're struggling with a subject. Reach out to your teachers, classmates,
              or tutors for assistance. Joining study groups can also provide support and enhance learning.






              10. Stay Positive and Motivated
              Maintain a positive attitude towards your studies. Celebrate your achievements, no matter how small,
              and stay motivated by reminding yourself of your goals and the reasons for pursuing them.






              By  implementing  these  practical  tips,  you  can  enhance  your  study  habits,  improve  your  academic
              performance, and achieve excellence in your studies.
              Remember, consistency and perseverance are key to success!







           B. How to Prepare for Exams without Stress ?

                   Start early: review material weeks in advance.
                   Break study material into manageable sections.
                   Use active recall and self-testing.
                   Practice with past papers and sample questions.
                    Get enough sleep and take regular breaks.
                    Eat well and stay hydrated during exam periods.]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[TECHNICAL AND















                                 SCIENTIFIC














                                      REVIEWS]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[Technical and scientific reviews


              A  collection  of  important  books  and  references  for


              every student is available in the college library:





             1.   An Introduction to Practical Biochemistry

             2.   Textbook of Forensic Chemistry

             3.   Bioinformatics A practical Guide to Next Generation
             Sequencing Data Analysis

             4.   Endocrine Biochemistry

             5.   CONSICE BOOK OF MEDICAL LABORATORY TECHNOLOGY:

             METHODS & INTERPRETATIONS
             6.   Nutrition science 2Ed

             7.   Diagnostic Pathology: Current Techniques

             8.   Global Health and Global Health Ethics
             9.   Principles of Biostatistics

             10. Parasitology: A Conceptual Approach

             11. TEXTBOOK OF CRITICAL CARE

             12.  HANDBOOK OF MEDICAL LABORATORY TECHNOLOGY (A
             BOOK FOR DMLT STUDENTS)

             13.   Medical Image Synthesis : Methods and Clinical

             Applications ( Imaging in Medical Diagnosis and Therapy)

             Paperback
             14.   Quality Assurance and Control in Diagnostic Radiology and

             Imaging

             15.   TEXTBOOK FOR X-RAY TECHNICIANS]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[The Role of Artificial Intelligence in Education


              Artificial  Intelligence  (AI)  is  revolutionizing  various  sectors,  and  higher
              education  is  no  exception.  The  integration  of  AI  in  university  education  is
              transforming  traditional  teaching  methods,  enhancing  learning  experiences,

              and providing personalized education to university students.




              Personalized Learning


              One  of  the  most  significant  impacts  of  AI  in  education  is  personalized  learning.  AI  algorithms  can
              analyze  students'  learning  patterns,  strengths,  and  weaknesses  to  tailor  educational  content  to  their
              individual needs. This ensures that each student receives a customized learning experience, which can
              improve understanding and retention of information.




              Intelligent Teaching Systems
              AI-powered  tutoring  systems  provide  students  with  additional  support  outside  the  classroom.  These
              systems  can  offer  explanations,  answer  questions,  and  provide  feedback  on  assignments,  helping
              students to learn at their own pace. This is particularly beneficial for students who may need extra help
              or those who want to advance more quickly.




              Administrative Efficiency

              AI  can  also  streamline  administrative  tasks,  such  as  grading  and  scheduling.  Automated  grading
              systems  can  quickly  and  accurately  assess  student  work,  freeing  up  teachers'  time  to  focus  on
              instruction  and  student  interaction.  AI  can  also  assist  in  creating  optimized  schedules  that  consider
              various factors, such as teacher availability and student needs.




              Enhanced Engagement
              Interactive AI tools, such as chatbots and virtual assistants, can engage students in new and exciting
              ways.  These  tools  can  answer  questions,  provide  resources,  and  even  facilitate  group  discussions,
              making learning more interactive and enjoyable.




              Data-Driven Insights
              AI  can  analyze  vast  amounts  of  educational  data  to  provide  insights  into  student  performance  and
              behavior.  Educators  can  use  this  data  to  identify  trends,  predict  outcomes,  and  make  informed
              decisions to improve teaching strategies and student support.





           Conclusion

           In  conclusion,  AI  is  playing  a  crucial  role  in  modernizing  higher  education.  By  providing
           personalized  learning  experiences,  supporting  university  student  with  intelligent  tutoring
           systems, enhancing administrative efficiency, and offering data-driven insights, AI is helping to
           create a more effective and engaging educational environment.]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[EDITORIAL BOARD














           &  SPECIAL THANKS]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[EDITORIAL




                                             BOARD






             Editor in chief


             Prof. Dr. Rasha Fathy Barwa







             Editors:




             Prof Dr. Rania Ramadan Abdelaziz



             Ass. Prof. Marwa Elsayed Abdelmageed



             Ass. Lec. Esraa Gamal El-din El-waseif




             Ass. Lec. Aamal Gamal El-din El-waseif



             Ass. Lec. Rana Mohammed Gamal



             D. Yasmin Abed El-mansey



             D. Samaa sameh Bakr



             Ms. Amira Ahmed Hassan Mohamed























                                                Graphic Designer:
                                                Ahmed Mohammed]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[SPECIAL




                                          THANKS






             Special thanks to Faculty staff:



             Prof. Areej Mostafa El-mahdy



             Prof. Manar Ahmed Nader El-Sayed


             Ass. Prof. Ahmed Ramadan El-Sheakh


             Ass. Prof. Eman Mohammed Anwar EL-Gendy



             Ass. Prof. Rehab Hamadtoh AbulGhait Gohar


             Ass. Prof. Mona Ahmed Sameeh Ragii Fouda


             Ass. Prof. Asmaa Ibrahem Abo Seada


             Dr. Nermin Ali Abd El-hakim Ali



             Dr. Enas El Sayed Mohamed Abdelrahman


             Dr. Ibrahim Attia Al-Mahdi


             Ass. Lec. Esraa Gamal El-din El-waseif



             Ass. Lec. Aamal Gamal El-din El-waseif


             Ass. Lec. Omar Wahba


             Ass. Lec. Yaser Ahmed


             Ass. Lec. Ahmed Samir Abdelazeem Gardouh]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[SPECIAL




                                          THANKS






             Special thanks to Faculty staff:




             D. Habiba mohamed abdelaziz


             D. Ali Azab Elsayed Ali


             D. Zuhir Magdy


             D. Mohamed El-Saied Mohamed Sanad


             D. Ahmed Akram Ali Ghanem




             Thanks to our students:



             Adham Mohammed Mahmoud


             Abdel Rahman Shehata Hessien



             Amal Sherif El Sayed

             Ammar Farid Mahmoud Amraa


             Eman Fathy Mahmoud


             Farah Salah Farouk


             Hagar Ali Yahia


             Hames Ahmed Ismail Hassan


             Ingy Zaghloul Abdel Samea


             Mariam Ehab Ali Hasanin


             Rawan Massad Massad Abu Al-Ma'at



             Sara Hamada El Mongy]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[Faculty of Health Science Technology -


                       Mansoura National University












                     international  Coastal Road -15th of May  District

                     - Gamasa City -Dakhalia Government








                      hscitechfac@mansnu.edu.eg








         PREPARED BY
         Ahmed Mohamed















         ﺔﻴﻠﻜﻟا ﺔﺤﻔﺻ     ﺔﻌﻣﺎﺠﻟا ﻊﻗﻮﻣ      ﺔﻌﻣﺎﺠﻟا ﻪﺤﻔﺻ



                      vol. 1- Issue 1]]></page></pages></Search>